<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>project on Nikolaus Piccolotto</title>
    <link>https://npiccolotto.com/tags/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in project on Nikolaus Piccolotto</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://npiccolotto.com/tags/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tiles</title>
      <link>https://npiccolotto.com/tiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://npiccolotto.com/tiles/</guid>
      <description>I am sharing one early project in my Ph.D. that I could not get published. I think it is kind of cute and it would be a shame if I&amp;rsquo;d just delete it. It&amp;rsquo;s a way to overlay spatial locations by non-overlapping grid cells which are aligned only on one axis. The other axis is free so as to better capture the point cloud&amp;rsquo;s outline. Reviewers sort of liked it but rejected our submissions because the produced partition does not have well-defined properties, such as optimal outline-tracking, minimum number of cells, lower bound on covered locations, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ph.D.</title>
      <link>https://npiccolotto.com/ph.d./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://npiccolotto.com/ph.d./</guid>
      <description>I defended my Ph.D.! You can find my thesis here, if you are interested.
The context of my research was a statistical analysis method that one could summarize as &amp;ldquo;Principal Component Analysis for Temporal or Spatial Data&amp;rdquo;. The method has certain properties that can improve/ease the analysis and modeling of temporal/spatial datasets, but it does not come for free: Challenges when applying the method are the intricate and vast parameter space and the amount of components to compare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel with Spotify</title>
      <link>https://npiccolotto.com/travel-with-spotify/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://npiccolotto.com/travel-with-spotify/</guid>
      <description>When I travel I like to get a feeling for the music from the place I will visit. Who are the romantic singers one should know? What was the popular boyband in the 90s? For a recent trip I copied artist names from a Wikipedia page into the Spotify search, and that clearly doesn&amp;rsquo;t scale.
Prior Art There are several playlists from Spotify for kind of this purpose (&amp;ldquo;The Needle&amp;rdquo;), but they give me popular music in that place, ie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glitch</title>
      <link>https://npiccolotto.com/glitch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://npiccolotto.com/glitch/</guid>
      <description>You probably came across some visuals that can be categorized as Glitch Art. For instance, it’s heavily used in Pony Island as you modify the code and break out of the haunted arcade machine.
I generally like this style a lot and wanted to find out what needs to be done to glitch some images of classic art. As somebody already did it for the PNG format, I focused on JPEG.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Correct Calculator</title>
      <link>https://npiccolotto.com/correct-calculator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://npiccolotto.com/correct-calculator/</guid>
      <description>Bugs are a long-standing problem in the software industry: Invisible characters crash iOS Messages. FaceTime enables microphone before the call starts.. An integer underflow causes Gandhi to be super-aggressive in the original Civilization. There are many more examples.
One way to achieve code correctness that was always mysterious to me is formal verification: You prove logically that the code does what you claim. (NB: It’s not the only nor the best nor most efficient way to achieve the goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>symdiff: prevent dead css</title>
      <link>https://npiccolotto.com/symdiff-prevent-dead-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://npiccolotto.com/symdiff-prevent-dead-css/</guid>
      <description>Some time ago I wrote a gulp plugin to enforce clean CSS in your frontend build. The idea, which I have from Github, is to break said build when the sets of classes in CSS and templates are not equal. This way you make sure you’re always actually using the styles you define and keep the amount of classes in your templates to a minimum.
I find it very useful and as of time of writing some 230 people on Github agree with me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>underlin.es</title>
      <link>https://npiccolotto.com/underlin.es/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://npiccolotto.com/underlin.es/</guid>
      <description>You know all the CSS generators like CSSmatic or CSS arrow please? I was looking for something similar, but for Medium-style text underlines (using background-image) and, strangely, unable to find it. So here it is: underlin.es.
It’s called “underlin.es” like it was hosted on underlin.es, but it’s not. Originally I had the intention to, but at 1:30 AM I just wanted to get it done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diploma</title>
      <link>https://npiccolotto.com/diploma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://npiccolotto.com/diploma/</guid>
      <description>My thesis project: A semantically-aided user assistance system for a composite information visualization system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FurPle</title>
      <link>https://npiccolotto.com/furple/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://npiccolotto.com/furple/</guid>
      <description>Back from the days in university: In a two-week seminar we built an app for Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s giant screen-as-a-table. The idea is to make furniture planning possible without physically moving furniture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tophat 2K</title>
      <link>https://npiccolotto.com/tophat-2k/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://npiccolotto.com/tophat-2k/</guid>
      <description>Back from the days in university: In the seminar for haptic interaction we (Fabian Prager, Christopher Bellmann and me) built a tangible user interface that ought to help with private car sharing. Done with an Arduino of course.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
